MSc. Albi Dode



Summary

Software Engineer/Developer, IT Support, Manual Tester, Technical Writer, and Data Protection Officer providing technical support, developing software programs, web sites, giving information security/DPO consultancy. I have knowledge in Agile methodology for leading teams in achieving excellence in client satisfaction, productivity, and profitability. Firm mindset with a drive to find solutions to new problems. Strong analytical skills and detailed to project's requirements. Adaption well in groups and a willingness to understand the various roles played by fellow team members. Perform tests and find ways to eliminate bugs in the programs. Build interactive and dynamic websites and experience with remote projects.

Work experience

IT Support 2021

astraia software gmbh

- Support a wide range of technical and network solutions including Windows, MAC and monitoring of the systems.
- Gather and analyse information about the user's issue in order to determine the best way to resolve their problem.
- Point of contact for Windows Server issues troubleshooting and Database back ups & transferring (Sybase+PostgreSQL).
- Prepare and conduct technical and application trainings.
- Co-operate with our Sales and Product Management department.
- Make use of XML, Java, SQL skills for data analysis.
- Optimize IT Support workflow.

IT Support 2021 - 2021

Leipzig International School

- IT Service Desk Solve ticket issues. Networking, Switches and Routing support. Data Backups. Update website and user manuals. Manage the wireless accounts.
- Configuration and maintenance of physical hardware components.
- Requirement analysis from different data analysis.
- Support for Windows& Mac (Office 365 & Active Directory).
- Remote & In-place support (Software & Hardware).
- Provide ideas in meetings for new technical requirements and actual project scope.

Researcher 2019 - 2021

ESIT & University of Ulm

Development of a generic framework for mobile data sensing and mobile patient intervention for tinnitus patients. Data analysis and articles publications.

Collect, analyse and publish data related scientific articles. * Support for
monitoring, measuring and researching large amounts of data coming from
TrackYourTinnitus smartphone application. * Help in code troubleshooting and
maintenance. * Help bachelor and master students prepare their thesis
preparation and writing. * Development of new ideas related to the tinnitus topic
through extensive data analysis and visualizations results from machine learning

Skills

Languages & Databases

C++, C#, VB .Net, Java, Python, HTML/SQL/PHP, R, Sybase, PostfreSQL, MySQL

Applications

Active Directory, GIT, Dita XML, Veeam, Baramundi, Ranorex, WireShark, Postman, CAS, Confluence, Zammad, Jira, LogicMonitor, WEKA, KNIME

Competencies

- Handle multiple projects simultaneously
- Prioritisation skills
- Troubleshooting
- Analytical skills
- Network
- Coding
- Technical Support
- Quality Assurance
- Research in new technologies

Languages

English, Italian, Spanish, Swedish, German

Certification

GDPR - DPO
Startup Winner

and algorithms implementation. * Take part in scientific conferences. * Co-author in different scientific articles with data analysis.

PHP Developer

2019 - 2019

BlueScreen

Develop back-end components, connect the application with other web services in PHP and SQL. * White Box testing of the final version.

Technical Writer

2018 - 2019

Ericsson

Understood different user levels and writes to the appropriate level. * Adhered to department and company standards, including templates and style guides. * Wrote and explained code, operational procedures, APIs and manuals. * Produced electronic documentation in addition to hard copy materials. * Maintained a comprehensive library of technical terminology and documentation (via GIT checks). * Analysed documents written in different tools and different projects to maintain continuity of the style of content. * Managed updates and revisions to technical literature.

IT and DPO 2018 - 2018

qPharmetra Sweden

* Cisco Meraki for cloud management, VPN networking, and application control. * Configure switches and Backups. IT support for Windows & Windows Server. * Office 365 & Active Directory and SharePoint support. * Use Veeam Backups. * Remote & In place support. * Point of contact for internal and external partners.

Lecturer 2015 - 2015

Albanian University Tirana

Lecturer and for one semester in Tirana and Berat for the subjects : Computer Architecture & Web Applications.

IT support 2014 - 2015

Albanian Psychologists Association

* Made a website using in HTML/PHP/MySql and a documentation content management system using Java. * Investigate faults in the network. * Procure network equipment according to needs. * Provide Windows & Windows Server support. * Perform backups. * Remote & In place support.

Technical Support Specialist

2012 - 2014

Albanian Business Partner

*Design and implement new network solution. *Facilitated network support for hospitals in Tirana for a software written in Java. * Windows support. * Remote & In place support. * Point of contact for internal and external partners.

Education

Bachelor in Computer Science

2010 - 2014

State University of New York

Master of Science in Software Engineering

2015 - 2017

Mälardalen University